Kahin Akram

Data Scientist | Ph.D. in Visualization

SUMMARY

Data scientist with 5+ years of experience in creative research thinking and quantitative/qualitative data analysis. Achievements include Ph.D. in abstract information visualization from Linköping University, data scientist at Scania Group, and leading UX/UI related projects.

EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST | SCANIA GROUP

Jan 2022 - present | Stockholm | Remote

- → Performed data preprocessing and used unsupervised learning to analyze charging log data from Scania's new electrical vehicles. I also lead two other data scientists in helping with the analysis and delivery of an exploratory proof-of-concept dashboard.
- → **Key achievements:** Delivered a tailor-made dashboard for better problem-specific data analysis, lead the project into completion, and presented the results (written and oral).
- → **Used:** Python, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn (unsupervised, PCA/t-SNE, Apriori/Eclat), Dash Plotly, and Data Storytelling.

KANBAN PRODUCT OWNER | TECHFORGOOD AS

Jan 2022 – present | Norrköping | Remote

- → Collaborated with stakeholders to articulate product vision and project implementation. Also, translated features into user stories within the team's backlog while managing, ranking, and prioritizing the list to reflect stakeholder's requirements.
- → Key achievements: Lead the team to an early MVP of the company website.
- → Used: Kanban, Figma, Trello

PROJECT LEADER | Norrköping Science Park

Apr 2021 – Sep 2021 | Norrköping | On-site

- → Project leader for a team of six to prepare the application for a European Digital Innovation Hub initiative with a focus on aviation in the greater Norrköping area.
- → **Key achievements:** Lead the team, structured and organized the project.
- → **Used:** Kanban Methodology, Trello, Teams, etc.

PROJECTS

PRIVATE CLOUD WITH NEXTCLOUD | RASPBERRY PI

Ongoing

→ To ensure my data is safe and private, I'm currently setting up my own cloud using Nextcloud running in a docker image on a Raspberry Pl.

OWN VPN WITH WIREGUARD | RASPBERRY PI

Ongoing

→ To feel safe while surfing I also setup my own VPN using Wireguard. The project is currently running in a docker image on a Raspberry PI.

CONTACT

- linkedin.com/in/kahinakram
- github.com/KahinAkramHassan
- ⋈ kahin.akram.hassan@gmail.com
- +46 (0)70 494 13 59

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Main:

Python

Secondary:

SQL • JavaScript

LIBRARIES/FRAMEWORKS

Flask • Scikit-Learn • Dash

Plotly • D3.js/Chart.js

TOOLS/PLATFORMS

Git • Docker • Raspberry Pi • OS(macOS, Linux, Windows)

CREATIVE

Figma • LAT_EX • Workshop planning • Agile Dev.

LANGUAGES

Native: Kurdish •

Proficiency: English, Swedish • Hobbyist: Spanish, Arabic

EDUCATION

LINKÖPING UNIVERSITY

Ph.D. IN INFORMATION VISUALIZATION

Jun 2016 - Mar 2021 | Sweden

LINKÖPING UNIVERSITY

B.Sc. & M.Sc. IN MEDIA TECHNOLOGY AND ENGINEERING Aug 2010 - Jun 2015 | Sweden